<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Tyler Robertson</title>
<link>https://aTylerRobertson.com</link>
<description>
A growing collection of blog posts from Tyler Robertson
</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>aTylerRobertson+rss@gmail.com (Tyler Robertson)</webMaster>
<atom:link href="https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<item><title>Well, well, well...</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/well-well-well</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>Well, well, well...</h1>

<p>Look who said they wouldn't roll their own blog and RSS, and here they are anyway!</p>

<p>This is all super basic, feel free to check out the <a href="https://github.com/aTylerRobertson/aTylerRobertson">source code</a> in the usual place. I'll be using it mostly for unserious writing, don't expect big tech guides or anything. <i>(that's coming in the book 👀)</i></p>
]]></description><pubDate>11/13/25 21:08:57</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/well-well-well</guid></item>
<item><title>What do you do with a fascist spreadsheet?</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/what-do-you-do-with-a-fascist-spreadsheet</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>What do you do with a fascist spreadsheet?</h1>

<p>Well, I guess they're evil now. 404 Media <i>(go support independent journalism)</i> <a href="https://www.404media.co/google-has-chosen-a-side-in-trumps-mass-deportation-effort/">has a report up now</a> about how Google is hosting an app designed to help ICE "identify immigrants", which is... pretty fascist behavior. Meanwhile, Microsoft seems pretty chill about them <a href="https://www.avclub.com/microsoft-mum-ice-trump-halo-imagery">using Halo as a recruitment ad</a>, and the <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-employees-protest-stop-work-with-ice-over-cruel-border-policies/">long-standing contract ICE has with GitHub</a>. Does this mean that using Google Sheets, Microsoft Excel, or even hosting my site on GitHub Pages like I do right now are acts in support of fascism? </p>

<p>I mean... probably not directly, right? But it's something to consider, especially now that I'm thinking about moving back into the world of writing about these kinds of tools. It's not going to be enough to use a tool from a fascist company in a non-fascist way (the medium is the message, etc.), so the work itself has to be anti-fascist from end to end. <i>Antifasheets</i>, if you will. </p>

<p>I don't know what that looks like yet. Is <a href="https://www.libreoffice.org">LibreOffice</a> any good? Do I roll my own thing, like I'm doing <a href="/">on my homepage</a>? Suggestions welcome. </p>
]]></description><pubDate>11/14/25 13:31:24</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/what-do-you-do-with-a-fascist-spreadsheet</guid></item>
<item><title>Disorganized thoughts of the week - Friday, November 21</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/disorganized-friday-nov-21</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>Disorganized thoughts of the week - Friday, November 21</h1>

<p>After all that work to get the new blog set up, I nearly forgot I had it! Haven't had the energy to put together a full post on anything this week, so here's a collection of thoughts from the week that I want to talk about and might put more words to soon.</p>

<h2><a href="#Brand vs. Hobby">Brand vs. Hobby</a></h2>

<p>I've been thinking about my <a href="../what-do-you-do-with-a-fascist-spreadsheet/">previous post</a> and can't shake the harm that branding — as a concept — has done to tech. It's never enough for something to be "just a bit of code", it has to have a clever name and logo to associate it with, or else people won't take it seriously. That's "hobby code". And then when there <i>is</i> a brand name to go along with it, your Googles and Microsofts of the world, it's trusted implicitly, even when it shouldn't be. I'm sure this isn't a new problem, but it does feel pretty related to recent events, especially thinking about how various AI products now all have catchy, human-sounding names. They're all <i>just code</i>, but the brand plays a powerful part in how people interact with them. </p>

<p>Going back to the spreadsheet of it all, I do feel like the next thing I want to focus on is something more <i>conceptually complete</i> than <i>marketable</i>, maybe extending something like this <a href="../bookmarklet-spreadsheet/">bookmarklet spreadsheet</a> so the tool can exist on its own and separate from any one brand or person. </p>
                
<h2><a href="#Software Engineering is a Sales job">Software Engineering is a Sales job</a></h2>

<p>Related to the whole branding thought is that I've just had an interview for a senior role at my company, and feel like more and more the job of a software engineer is more about sales than coding ability. For example, you have to know which Amazon product best suits a given scenario, and how to adjust your AWS usage to fit a budget. Or you have to explain your AI prompt process, and why you prefer Claude over Copilot. And then if you're lucky there's a <i>tiny</i> bit of coding for you to do, but you have to make sure you're following the standards that Meta gave a cute brand name to. </p>

<p>Which is all... <i>fine</i>, I guess, but we can't do that <i>and</i> tell people just starting in the industry that it's a career full of puzzle solving and critical thinking. (Though now that I've said that I'm sure that illusion will die the second any of them meet a manager.) </p>

<h2><a href="#Trans Day of Remembrance">Trans Day of Remembrance</a></h2>

<p>Trans Day of Remembrance was yesterday, and like always I nearly forget until about 10pm. I'm glad it exists, but I wish everyone did more to make it so trans people are known and cared for while still living. </p>

<h2><a href="#NoctHorror 2026">NoctHorror 2026</a></h2>

<p>We're wrapping up our annual Halloween movie festival! (It used to be called <i>OctHorror</i> but we've been creeping further and further into November) I'll do a full write-up of it next month, but I've been very happy with my video setup this year, which involves an HDMI-to-analog converter that I <i>highly</i> recommend to anyone who streams and likes that SD video look. Our screenings had the vibe of watching VHS tapes with friends, and I had a load of fun making it all work.</p>

<p>The big difference this year was that I kept the films a secret until the day before each screening, but would send puzzles with hints towards the film and their order. So before each film they could guess what the upcoming films would be, and get more points based on how far ahead they could accurately guess. A few people did really well! Some of the clues are very dependent on inside jokes so I'll only share some in the full write-up, but the morale of the story is that we should all be making puzzles for our friends. </p>
]]></description><pubDate>11/21/25 15:43:37</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/disorganized-friday-nov-21</guid></item>
<item><title>NoctHorror 2025!</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/nocthorror</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>NoctHorror 2025!</h1>

<p>This weekend, my partner and I wrapped up the sixth annual <i>NoctHorror</i> (formerly <i>OctHorror</i>, renamed because it kept creeping further and further into November), our annual Spooky Season film festival we do for our friends. Normally, we watch 13 films over Zoom and wrap the month with a pub quiz about those films, but this year I went a little overboard and made the <i>films themselves</i> into the puzzle. I kept all 13 films a secret until 24 hours before each screening, and sent the players puzzles along the way so they could try and suss them out, as well as an overarching mystery. There's a lot of internal lore that's built up over the last six years, so sharing all of the clues won't make a ton of sense, but check out this tube map I made for one of them:</p>

<img alt="tube map" src="images/Nocthorror<i>tube</i>map.svg" />

<p>The symbols on the left are part of the "ancient language Dra-Q-Lese" spoken by long-time antagonist "Count Dra-Q-La", and the map points the players both towards the next three films in the series and hints at the broader theme of the month, which culminated in drawing a giant pentagram on a map to triangulate the Count's hideout. I was even extra-devious this year and made some of the stops clickable in the PDF, so savvy players could uncover hidden mini-quizzes that netted them extra points in the finale. I'm extremely proud of it, but <i>woof</i> am I tired. 😅 Part of this year's event was a symbolic "passing the torch", and I'm excited for someone else to take the reins next year, at least when it comes to picking the films.</p>

<p>This year, we watched:</p>

<ol>
<li>A Quiet Place</li>
<li>Bodies Bodies Bodies</li>
<li>Poseidon</li>
<li>247℉</li>
<li>Let It Snow (2020)</li>
<li>Saloum</li>
<li>Anaconda</li>
<li>Bacurau</li>
<li>In the Shadows in the Mountains</li>
<li>The Edge of the Shadows</li>
<li>The Platform</li>
<li>Omen</li>
<li>Congo</li>
</ol>

<p>And before you even start — I <i>know</i> that some of those aren't horror films. I was going for a whole geographical theme, it all made sense in the end.</p>

<p>Of the selection this year, I liked <i>Saloum</i> and <i>Bacurau</i> the best (RIP Udo Kier), and despite <i>Omen</i> being a straight-up drama (despite what the trailer and marketing sell it as), I recommend that to pretty much anybody. <i>In the Shadows in the Mountains</i> and <i>The Edge of the Shadows</i> aren't good movies by any means (sorry, Malik), but it was so cool to see a Greenland local's take on their folklore.</p>

<p>Because we started this tradition deep in the COVID-19 pandemic, all of our screenings were over Zoom, which is a legally dark-gray area, but <b>hypothetically</b> one way to facilitate this sort of thing is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Buy as many of the films as possible on DVD</li>
<li>Hook your DVD player into an HDMI switcher (so you can swap between it and your Nintendo Switch and your Apple TV)</li>
<li>Make sure your 
<li>Plug the output of the switcher into an HDMI splitter</li>
<li>Take one of the outputs from the splitter and plug it into your TV</li>
<li>Take the other end of the splitter and plug it into an HDMI-to-Analog converter (for example a <i>Mini HDMI2AV Upscaler 1080p</i>, hypothetically)</li>
<li>Take an RCA cable from the output of the converter into an Analog to USB Video Capture Device (there are a hundred generic versions of these)</li>
<li>Optionally, use a USB to USB-C converter to plug that into your laptop</li>
<li>Use <a href="https://obsproject.com">OBS Studio</a> to take in the audio and video from the caputure device, making sure to add any necessary filters to account for "buzz" that might happen during the analog conversion</li>
<li>Start the OBS virtual camera</li>
<li>Open Zoom or your video communication app of choice</li>
<li>Set your camera and microphone to the OBS virtual camera (and make sure to enable any "high-quality audio for musicians" settings)</li>
</ul>

<p>And <i>voila</i>! Hypothetically, you'll be watching your favorite films with your friends, as though you were all in the same room together. The digital-to-analog conversion helps make sure DRM won't stop you, and gives everything an actually pretty pleasant late-VHS/early-DVD vibe.</p>

<p>In case you're looking for any further inspiration (or if you're me next year, trying to remember this), here's what we watched for previous NoctHorrors:</p>

<h2><a href="#2024">2024</a></h2>

<p>This year we had a "teen horror" theme, with everyone picking cabins in the fictional "Camp Dra-Q-La" and competing for prizes throughout the month. We watched:</p>

<ol>
<li>Jennifer's Body</li>
<li>Ginger Snaps</li>
<li>I Know What You Did Last Summer</li>
<li>Final Destination</li>
<li>Fright Night (1985)</li>
<li>House of Wax (2005)</li>
<li>The Lost Boys</li>
<li>Chopping Mall</li>
<li>Jeepers Creepers</li>
<li>The Funhouse</li>
<li>Happy Death Day</li>
<li>Sleepaway Camp</li>
<li>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</li>
</ol>

<h2><a href="#2023">2023</a></h2>

<p>This was our first themed year where we voted for "space", so naturally I included a fully-voiced HAL 9000 to "help" me run the quiz (I did, somehow, shove him out an airlock in the end).</p>

<ol>
<li>The Day the Earth Stood Still (1951)</li>
<li>Killer Klowns from Outer Space</li>
<li>Plan 9 from Outer Space</li>
<li>The Thing</li>
<li>Jason X</li>
<li>Leprechaun 4</li>
<li>Hellraiser IV: Bloodline</li>
<li>Planet of the Vampires</li>
<li>Solaris (1972)</li>
<li>Event Horizon</li>
<li>Sunshine</li>
<li>Predator</li>
<li>Alien</li>
</ol>

<h2><a href="#2022">2022</a></h2>

<p>This was before we were officially doing themes, but even then I was always playing with the idea of how each film could relate to the next one, so the whole thing had kind of a semi-logical flow to it.</p>

<ol>
<li>Dracula</li>
<li>The Wolf Man</li>
<li>Monster House</li>
<li>The Cabin in the Woods</li>
<li>The Evil Dead</li>
<li>Drag Me To Hell</li>
<li>Friday the 13th (2009)</li>
<li>Halloween 3: Season of the Witch</li>
<li>Old</li>
<li>Us</li>
<li>Parasite</li>
<li>Pet Sematary (2019)</li>
<li>Shaun of the Dead</li>
</ol>

<h2><a href="#2021">2021</a></h2>

<p>This was when we landed on doing 13 films for the event, which gave us a good (spooky) number and meant we could schedule it in a way that fit for more of our friends' schedules. As always, the real monster is "having other responsibilities"!</p>

<ol>
<li>The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari</li>
<li>Psycho</li>
<li>The Birds</li>
<li>Rosemary's Baby</li>
<li>Don't Look Now</li>
<li>The Texas Chainsaw Massacre</li>
<li>Halloween II</li>
<li>Bloodbath at the House of Death</li>
<li>Silence of the Lambs</li>
<li>Candyman (1992)</li>
<li>Mary Shelley's Frankenstein</li>
<li>It Follows</li>
<li>One Cut of the Dead</li>
</ol>

<h2><a href="#2020">2020</a></h2>

<p>We started this right in the middle of a lockdown, half out of our minds anyway, and just needed to do <i>something</i>. So we thought it would be a good idea to watch one movie every night for the entire month of October. And it was a good idea at the time! Just... not one I'd do again.</p>

<ol>
<li>Hocus Pocus</li>
<li>The Addams Family</li>
<li>Sleepy Hollow</li>
<li>Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street</li>
<li>Corpse Bride</li>
<li>The Craft</li>
<li>Halloweentown</li>
<li>The Blair Witch Project</li>
<li>The Frighteners</li>
<li>Halloween</li>
<li>The Shining</li>
<li>Scream</li>
<li>The Mummy (1999)</li>
<li>Crimson Peak</li>
<li>Bram Stoker's Dracula</li>
<li>Rocky Horror Picture Show</li>
<li>The Sixth Sense</li>
<li>The Faculty</li>
<li>Death Becomes Her</li>
<li>Coraline</li>
<li>The Wicker Man (1973)</li>
<li>The Wicker Man (2006)</li>
<li>Pan's Labyrinth</li>
<li>Monster Squad</li>
<li>Carrie (1976)</li>
<li>Under Wraps</li>
<li>Nosferatu</li>
<li>Hellraiser</li>
<li>Beetlejuice</li>
<li>Young Frankenstein</li>
</ol>
]]></description><pubDate>11/24/25 19:50:48</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/nocthorror</guid></item>
<item><title>A spreadsheet is a war of attrition</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/a-spreadsheet-is-a-war-of-attrition</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>A spreadsheet is a war of attrition</h1>

<p>Something I'll start writing about more here — so that you'll keep me accountable, if nothing else — is that I'm starting to write a book.</p>

<p>Specifically, I'm starting to write a book about spreadsheets, and what they are, and what they can do. I've been trying to isolate what specifically I'm drawn to in this subject, and just now my partner pulled up <a href="https://royaldrawingschool.org/events/drawing-dialogues-with-sir-grayson-perry-ra">this talk</a> with Sir Grayson Perry. When talking about his process, he said (paraphrasing), "I'm not one of these artists who comes in with an effortless line. My art is more like a <b>war of attrition</b>." In Perry's art, that lust for war comes from his love of outsider art, and building up a piece of art through painstaking little steps of process and craft, rather than effortlessly falling into something. And this will sound crazy, but:</p>

<b>Spreadsheets are a war of attrition.</b>

<p>When I was making video games in spreadsheets, using only built-in functions, it wasn't intended to be a showcase of my own technical mastery; kind of the opposite, actually. What I <i>wanted</i> to do (best laid plans and all that) was show what could be built up from a modest and boring starting place if you pour enough time and careful thought into it. It was a million tiny knife strokes in code instead of paint, unobscured by the final piece.</p>

<p>That last part is just as important to me: when you as the user want to learn how a "good" spreadsheet works, those answers are there for you in the piece itself. That makes it a unique artform from apps or AI slop or any of the million bits of corporate code we interact with now, which hide their true forms away from you like that Simpsons meme where Homer's pinned all his fat back with chip clips and hair ties. We can't learn anything from those, because they resist being learned. But a spreadsheet bares its scars in the open for you, and there's something poetic and lovely about that that I want to share with you.</p>

<p>Anyway, so that's what the book's about. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>11/26/25 19:52:34</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/a-spreadsheet-is-a-war-of-attrition</guid></item>
<item><title>"Software engineer" is not written on my heart</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/software-engineer-is-not-written-on-my-heart</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>"Software engineer" is not written on my heart</h1>

<p>I applied for a job last month, an internal posting for the "senior" version of my current role, which is "software engineer". I didn't get the job, which is fine because I still have a job that I mostly enjoy, but I was confused by the feedback I received from the hiring panel: They said I demonstrated excellent communication, leadership, critical thinking skills, and a strong ability to act as a well-rounded full-stack engineer (meaning both "back end" code that you don't directly experience as a user and "front end" code which you do). They said, point of fact, that I would be good at the job. But I didn't get it because I lacked specific, deep knowledge of a product that I have never once had reason to use. </p>

<p>This struck me as unfair at the time, not only because the job spec didn't mention that product (and in fact appeared to be looking for generalists like myself), but the feedback of "gain specialized knowledge" carries the implied meta-commentary of "gain the <i>correct</i> specialized knowledge". Deepening one's knowledge of their work is never a bad thing, but in a field so broad as software engineering, it's sort of a crap-shoot as to whether your specialism will be the secret password into a new role unless it's explicitly advertised as such. They did not, for example, care about spreadsheets or database management for this particular role. There's also something to be said for skills refused with reason, like my "inexperience" with generative AI, which is very much on purpose. </p>

<p>I conveyed all this to my manager in a debrief chat after I'd heard the bad news, not to cast blame on anyone because all in all I think the hiring process was very well organized, but to try and parse why I seem to struggle so much with finding recognition in this field. After a bit of venting he said to me, <b>"Are you a software engineer in your heart? Because I don't think you are."</b></p>

<p>I was about ready to fight him on this, initially hearing it as a different way of saying "you aren't ready for the role", which always gets my hackles up. But saying it this way made me pause: am I a software engineer in my heart? Was I "born for this"? Am I, to be crude for a second, <i>horny for it?</i></p>

<p>And... no, I don't think I am. Or, at least not in the way the hiring panel was secretly looking for. Because when someone's real horny for this kind of work, real sopping wet for it you see, having a deep specialized knowledge in <i>everything</i> is just a way of life for them, as easy as breathing. The people who got the role didn't need to think about the overly specific questions that got sprung in the interview, because they (in some cases literally) were doing that work in their sleep, spending their free time reading AWS press releases and examining the differences between AI agents. The kind of software engineer that was in demand here, and maybe in demand everywhere (in which case I'm cooked), is absolutely horny for it. And that's... just not me. </p>

<p>While it's difficult to be told that you aren't "cut out" for your current career despite literal years of hardwork and being actually quite good at it in practice, I'm kind of relieved to have found this flaw in myself while still relatively early on. There's this Oscar Wilde quote that I've returned to a lot over the years that goes, <b>"If you want to be a grocer, or a general, or a politician, or a judge, you will invariably become it; that is your punishment. If you never know what you want to be, if you live what some might call the dynamic life but what I will call the artistic life, if each day you are unsure of who you are and what you know you will never become anything, and that is your reward."</b> If I wanted to be a software engineer, I have no doubt that I would become one, but in truth I have no idea what I want to be. I hope that means I'm living "the artistic life", but I think that will be up to those who outlive me tk decide. </p>

<p>Lord willing, and if the creek don't rise, I will continue to be gainfully employed in the role of "software engineer" for the foreseeable. I will get to keep engaging in the bits of it that tickle my brain, like reproducing strange bugs and planning for traffic spikes and fixing issues to make my colleagues' days easier. But "software engineer" is not what is written in my heart, and I hope that it is not a term that will appear in any eulogies of me when my time comes. To me, it's a job to have for now, and I'm happy to let others claim it as their life's calling. I would like to find my own one day, and hope that I can leave behind something good even if I don't. </p>
]]></description><pubDate>11/29/25 17:41:12</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/software-engineer-is-not-written-on-my-heart</guid></item>
<item><title>The Night Shift</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/the-night-shift</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>The Night Shift</h1>

<p>There's a thing that happens when you move timezones that no one really talks about. It's always there, but I find it's especially potent this time of year; when the days are shorter and the light dims to a constant cool grey. It's "the night shift".</p>

<p>Specifically what I mean by that is that, when you move far enough away from the important people in your life, every day starts to feel a bit like picking up a new shift at work, trading a 9am-5pm for a 9pm-5am. Your sleep schedule starts lining up with when your friends and family are at work, and you live for the little glimmers of time when you're awake at the same time as them, swapping stories over your dinner and their breakfast (or vice-versa). It can be a lonely thing, especially times like now when all of my friends back home are living the daily reality of a government crashing in around them. I'm sure for many of them think I disappeared or "got out", if they noticed at all that I'm no longer online at the same times they are.</p>

<p>But I don't say any of that to be sad about it, even if I am sometimes. Putting a name to it helps. I worried for a long time that people stopped reaching out because they resented me or my decision to move away, or maybe I just wasn't interesting anymore, but it's never anything like that really — most people don't think that way — it's just The Night Shift.</p>

<p>The temptation of The Night Shift is to lean into it; to stay up later than you normally would to see who logs in, to wait an extra few minutes for that friend to reply. But if you're in The Night Shift like I am, I'd encourage you to resist that as much as you can. Unless you have a long-distance community with very strict schedules, waiting for those messages that may never come can lead to more sleepless nights than you can afford this season. Certainly more than you deserve.</p>

<p>Instead I think the answer to the loneliness comes from the oncoming Autumn/Winter season we're rapidly approaching. When the common squirrel or magpie feels the temperature drop, they start building their little hidey-holes, their treasure chests of tasty treats that will help them survive the darkest months, and come back to reward them in the Spring. They know, in whatever instinctual animal form of knowing, that this practice is the stuff of life itself, and the preparation should be long and careful if it is to succeed at all. The same can, and I'd argue <i>should</i>, be a practice for us.</p>

<p>Even though our phones and laptops and tablets and watches <i>can</i> send messages across the globe instantly, we know from our experience in the Night Shift that expecting an immediate reply is purchasing an express ticket to the land of disappointment, on the cable car of self-inflicted rejection. And we <i>know</i> that that's no one's fault, but in the moment our feelings often override that logic, especially in the cold and dark. <i>But</i>, if we can flip that around and work slowly and intentionally at the practice of community, we can change the script from a defeat to a marching advance — building the messages up like Cold War secrets in a spy's dead drop, lying in wait to be received by our counterparts abroad. Changing the quick "hey" into poems and essays and love letters that say "yes, we're still here! we still care! and we know you do too."</p>

<p>It's... stupid, I know. Writing all of this is a bit of a faff and it's my way of saying <i>yes</i>, I'm still here, and I still care, and I know you do too. It's a hard time to stay in touch, especially when we're oceans apart and life is so much more difficult now. But I think we can do it if we do it slowly and with kindness for ourselves. We're all just doing our best.</p>

<p>Let us turn our tweets and skeets and snaps and bleets into acorns for the Winter. Seeds for the Spring. Letters from the Night Shift.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>12/16/25 19:55:17</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/the-night-shift</guid></item>
<item><title>Announcing the 2026 Rezzies</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/2026-rezzies</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>Announcing the 2026 Rezzies</h1>

<i>(I heard Producer Ben on</i> Blank Check with Griffin and David <i>say "rezzies" instead of "resolutions" and it stuck in my brain like a Kennedian worm, so here we are.)</i>

<p>New Year's Resolutions! They're a real crapshoot for me if we're being honest, and I've tried a half-dozen pretty jerk-off-motion ways of calling them by other names over the years. Big fan of the <a href="https://www.themesystem.com">Theme System</a> idea of having yearly <i>themes</i> instead of explicit resolutions, but I could never make that stick personally. I've also done yearly <i>recaps</i> instead to see if I felt better about annual retrospectives than look-aheads (I don't). But here I am back to plain old resolutions, declaring to the world that these are things I <i>want</i> to do in the next year, and releasing myself from any judgment if I don't get around to all of them for whatever reason. Hopefully, I think, putting some of this down in writing will spur me into action six, seven months from now when I've lost motivation again.</p>

<h2><a href="#Writing">Writing</a></h2>

<p>I've started working on a book! I'm a couple thousand words in and have an outline I feel good about already, but this coming year I want to set aside dedicated writing time to finish it up. </p>

<h2><a href="#Music">Music</a></h2>

<p>I used to play music, and don't so much anymore, but would like to again! This will require a bit of change in my home setup, as there's not really a place to play without disturbing neighbors, but hopefully with some good headphones I can make this happen.</p>

<h2><a href="#Sport">Sport</a></h2>

<p>I've started working out again recently, and want to get into a sport next year. Specifically, I'm really itching to lift/throw heavy things? </p>

<h2><a href="#Styling">Styling</a></h2>

<p>I feel strongly that Spring should come with a bit of a wardrobe shake-up for me, specifically leaning into more femme fashions and pieces that make me feel actually <i>sexy</i> over just <i>presentable</i>. Some skirts, some low-cut shirts, and showing off my arms and legs more will hopefully be in the cards soon. </p>

<p>2026 is also the year I want to start experimenting with makeup! I know myself well enough to know I won't like wearing <i>lots</i> of it, but there's little things I want to experiment with to shake up my daily look. </p>

<h2><a href="#Drag">Drag</a></h2>

<p>Related to the above, I really want to try performing in drag this year! I think I'd enjoy it, and I think I'd be good at it!</p>

<h2><a href="#Community">Community</a></h2>

<p>While I'm so glad that I've found queer people at work that I can spend small amounts of time with, those interactions are very much limited to the office, and I don't really have a community in London that I can share life events with yet. I want to change this, get some out-of-office friends in my area, and feel like I have a support network physically nearby (even though my remote support group is the best and I love you all, you're just an ocean a way is all). I'm in my 30s so I'm (as is my millennial birthright) not sure how to do this at all. I know a couple people who know a couple people involved in the local drag scene, so I'm wondering if that's secretly my way into checking off a few of these things at once. </p>

<h2><a href="#Huge birthday party">Huge birthday party</a></h2>

<p>My birthday is in June (every year!) and for my 35th I want to throw a big, fuck-off birthday party with a theme and costumes and prizes and merch and everything. I've already started drawing up some plans, and I'm about to start roping friends into contributing. </p>

<p>And I think that'll be my year! Fingers crossed I get at least a few of these things done. </p>
]]></description><pubDate>12/23/25 12:03:13</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/2026-rezzies</guid></item>
<item><title>Need the big screen for the little posts</title><link>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/big-screen-for-little-posts</link><description><![CDATA[
<h1>Need the big screen for the little posts</h1>

<p>Just thinking about what kind of blogging I want to do this year, and I think it's two things: I want to blog less seriously, but do it on the laptop instead of my phone. Originaly I came up with this whole system by which I could write on my phone and post from wherever, but in practice I think that made everything feel weirdly more and less formal than I want it. So... fuck that.</p>

<p>I remember reading somewhere (probably Instagram) that Millennials need big screens for big purchases, and won't buy flights or things like that on their phones, and while that is cringe in a uniquely Millennial way (the last generation capable of shame) I think I'm OK with that being true for writing.</p>

<p>Other than that, 2026 is off to a good start! I've got a tiny little diary (physical paper!) to help keep track of what I do each day, because 2025 felt like a blur, and I've done a nice little refresh on all my electronic devices to get a fresh-ish start to the year. Next week I should be getting some parts to do a final repair on my old GameBoy Color so it can be my commuting buddy again, and then I should be all set up to have a low-stress re-entry into the daily grind.</p>

<p>Toodles!</p>
]]></description><pubDate>01/02/26 12:59:00</pubDate><guid>https://aTylerRobertson.com/read/big-screen-for-little-posts</guid></item>
</channel>
</rss>
